Guide to the Christine Bose Collection on Marxist-Feminist Group 1 TAM.803
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Christine Bose Collection on Marxist-Feminist Group 1
1990-2021
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Bose, Christine E.
TAM.803
.5 linear feet in 1 manuscript box
51 Megabytes in 84 computer files
Christine E. Bose (1948- ) is an Affiliated Professor at the University of Washington, as well as Professor Emerita at University of Albany, SUNY, where she has held numerous appointments concerning Sociology and Women's Studies since 1978. Bose is the author or editor of multiple books on subjects such as women's employment, globalization and gender, household technology, and gender in Latin America. From the early 1990s until the 2020s, Bose has been an active member of the Marxist-Feminist Group 1 (MF1), a discussion group focusing on topics related to socialist feminism. The Christine Bose Collection on Marxist Feminist Group 1 consists of materials in paper and electronic format collected by Bose documenting the activities of MF1 from 1990-2021. The bulk of the collection consists of meeting agendas, minutes, handouts, and readings from the group, with a smaller amount of letters. Topics present in this collection include Black liberation, AIDS, fundamentalism and the Right, global economics, welfare, drug usage, and multiculturalism, reflecting prominent contemporary issues for which the group members want to develop a Marxist feminist analysis.
Scope and Contents
The Christine Bose Collection on Marxist Feminist Group 1 consists of materials in paper and electronic format collected by Bose documenting the activities of Marxist Feminist Group 1 (MF1) from 1990-2021. The bulk of the collection consists of meeting agendas, minutes, handouts, and readings from the group, with a smaller amount of letters. Topics present in this collection include Black liberation, AIDS, fundamentalism and the Right, global economics, welfare, drug usage, and multiculturalism, reflecting prominent contemporary issues for which the group members want to develop a Marxist feminist analysis.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Christine Bose in June 2021; the accession number associated with this gift is 2021.029.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically, maintaining the donor's original order.
Related Materials
Christine E. Bose Papers, 1975-1978 (Collection Number 6134), University of Washington Libraries, Special Collections
Biographical Note
Christine E. Bose (1948- ) is an Affiliated Professor at the University of Washington, as well as Professor Emerita at University of Albany, SUNY, where she has held numerous appointments concerning Sociology and Women's Studies since 1978. Bose is the author or editor of multiple books on subjects such as women's employment, globalization and gender, household technology, and gender in Latin America, including Women in the Latin American Development Process. She earned her B.A. in Mathematics from Wagner College (1969), and her Ph.D. in Sociology from Johns Hopkins University (1973). From the early 1990s until the 2020s, Bose has been an active member of the Marxist-Feminist Group 1 (MF1), a study and discussion group created in the 1970s for socialist feminists to partake in Marxist-feminist consciousness-raising in an environment free of the sexism many members experienced in other Marxist spaces.
Appraisal
Electronic documents concerning the donation of this collection to New York University have been appraised out of the collection.
Feminism; Capitalism.; Feminist theory.; Political science.; Communism.; Women and communism -- United States -- History -- 20th century.; Women and socialism -- United States.; Bose, Christine E.
- Saturday Planning Session, 1990-10-20 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letters, 1991-08 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- "Looking Forward: A Roundtable on Participatory Economics," Z Magazine, July-August 1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- "Impact of Feminism and Multiculturalism on Our Conceptions of the 'Canon' for the Modern Period", Winter 1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Handouts and Notes from Discussion Sessions, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Notes from Discussion Sessions and Conference Presentations, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Meeting Minutes, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Meeting Agendas, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Notes from New York City, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Meeting Minutes, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Meeting Agenda, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Meeting Agendas, Minutes, and Handouts, 2006; cuid34864 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Meeting Agenda, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Meeting Agendas, Minutes, and Handouts, 2008; cuid34865 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_803_ER_2)
- Meeting Agendas, Minutes, and Handouts, 2010; cuid34866 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_803_ER_3)
- Meeting Agendas, Minutes, and Handouts, 2011; cuid34867 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_803_ER_4)
- Meeting Agendas, Minutes, and Handouts, 2012; cuid34868 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_803_ER_5)
- Meeting Agendas, Minutes, and Handouts, 2013; cuid34869 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_803_ER_6)
- Meeting Agendas, Minutes, and Handouts, 2014; cuid34870 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_803_ER_7)
- Meeting Agendas, Minutes, and Handouts, 2015; cuid34871 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_803_ER_8)
- Meeting Agendas, Minutes, and Handouts, 2016; cuid34872 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_803_ER_9)
- Meeting Agendas, Minutes, and Handouts, 2017; cuid34873 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_803_ER_10)
- Meeting Agendas, Minutes, and Handouts, 2018; cuid34874 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_803_ER_11)
- Meeting Agendas, Minutes, and Handouts, 2019; cuid34875 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_803_ER_12)
- Meeting Agendas, Minutes, and Handouts, 2020; cuid34876 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_803_ER_13)
- Meeting Agendas, Minutes, and Handouts, 2021; cuid34877 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records TW_TAM_803_ER_14)